<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><book xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" version="5.1"><info xmlns:d="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
    <title xmlns:ns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">Clinical Decision Support (CDS) Content and
      Health Level 7 (HL7)-Compliant Knowledge Artifacts (KNARTs)</title>
    <subtitle xmlns:ns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">Mental Health: Military Sexual Trauma (MST)
      Clinical Content White Paper</subtitle>
    <copyright xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
      <year>2018</year>
      <holder>B3 Group, Inc.</holder>
    </copyright>
    <legalnotice xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
      <title>B3 Group, Inc.</title>
      <para>NOTICE OF GOVERNMENT COPYRIGHT LICENSE AND UNLIMITED RIGHTS LICENSE</para>
      <para>Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License"); you may not use this
        file except in compliance with the License.</para>
      <para>You may obtain a copy of the License at <link
          xlink:href="http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0"
          >http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0</link>
      </para>
      <para>Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software distributed under
        the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS, WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY
        KIND, either express or implied. See the License for the specific language governing
        permissions and limitations under the License.</para>
      <para>Portions of this content are derivative works from content produced by Cognitive Medical
        Systems, Inc. licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0.</para>
      <para>Additional portions of this content are derivative works from content contributed by
        Motive Medical Intelligence Inc., under Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0.</para>
      <para>Contributions from 2013-2018 were performed either by US Government employees, or under
        US Veterans Health Administration contracts.</para>
      <para>US Veterans Health Administration contributions by government employees are work of the
        U.S. Government and are not subject to copyright protection in the United States. Portions
        contributed by government employees are USGovWork (17USC §105). Not subject to
        copyright.</para>
      <para>See: <link xlink:href="https://www.usa.gov/government-works"
          >https://www.usa.gov/government-works</link>
      </para>
      <para>Contribution by contractors to the US Veterans Health Administration during this period
        are contractually contributed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 and US Government
        sponsorship is acknowledged under Contract VA118-16-D-1008, Task Order
        VA11817F10080007.</para>
    </legalnotice>
    <copyright xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
      <year>2018</year>
      <holder>Cognitive Medical Systems, Inc.</holder>
    </copyright>
    <legalnotice xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
      <title>Cognitive Medical Systems, Inc.</title>
      <para>Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License"); you may not use this
        file except in compliance with the License.</para>
      <para>You may obtain a copy of the License at <link
          xlink:href="http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0"
          >http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0</link>
      </para>
      <para>Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software distributed under
        the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS, WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY
        KIND, either express or implied. See the License for the specific language governing
        permissions and limitations under the License.</para>
      <para>This and related content produced by Cognitive Medical Systems, Inc. licensed under the
        Apache License, Version 2.0 is available at: <link
          xlink:href="https://bitbucket.org/cogmedsys/hl7-kas-examples"
          >https://bitbucket.org/cogmedsys/hl7-kas-examples</link>
      </para>
      <para>Additional portions of this content are derivative works from content contributed by
        Motive Medical Intelligence Inc., under Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0. <link
          xlink:href="https://bitbucket.org/cogmedsys/kas-source-material"
          >https://bitbucket.org/cogmedsys/kas-source-material</link>
      </para>
      <para>Contributions from 2013-2018 were performed either by US Government employees, or under
        US Veterans Health Administration contracts.</para>
      <para>US Veterans Health Administration contributions by government employees are work of the
        U.S. Government and are not subject to copyright protection in the United States. Portions
        contributed by government employees are USGovWork (17USC §105). Not subject to copyright.
        See: <link xlink:href="https://www.usa.gov/government-works"
          >https://www.usa.gov/government-works</link>
      </para>
      <para>Contribution by contractors to the US Veterans Health Administration during this period
        are contractually contributed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 and US Government
        sponsorship is acknowledged under Contract VA118-16-D-1008-0007.</para>
    </legalnotice>
    <authorgroup xmlns:ns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
      <author>
        <personname>Department of Veterans Affairs (VA)</personname>
      </author>
      <author>
        <orgname>
          <inlinemediaobject>
            <alt>Department of Veteran's Affairs Logo</alt>
            <imageobject>
              <imagedata contentwidth="2in" align="center" fileref="../resource/VASealColor.jpg"
                format="png"/>
            </imageobject>
          </inlinemediaobject></orgname>
      </author>
      <author>
        <orgname>Knowledge Based Systems (KBS)</orgname>
      </author>
      <author>
        <orgname>Office of Informatics and Information Governance (OIIG)</orgname>
      </author>
      <author>
        <orgname>Clinical Decision Support (CDS)</orgname>
      </author>
    </authorgroup>
    <abstract xmlns:ns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
      <info>
        <title>Contract: VA118-16-D-1008, Task Order (TO): VA-118-16-F-1008-0007</title>
      </info>
      <para>
        <table colsep="1" frame="all" rowsep="1">
          <title>Relevant KNART Information: Mental Health: Military Sexual Trauma (MST)</title>
          <tgroup align="left" cols="2">
            <thead>
              <row valign="bottom">
                <entry valign="middle">KNART Name</entry>
                <entry valign="middle">Associated CLIN</entry>
              </row>
            </thead>
            <tbody>
              <row>
                <entry>Military Sexual Trauma (MST) - Documentation Template</entry>
                <entry>CLIN0005AA</entry>
              </row>
            </tbody>
          </tgroup>
        </table>
      </para>
    </abstract>
    <pubdate xmlns:ns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">May 2018</pubdate>
    <volumenum xmlns:ns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">Version 1</volumenum>
  </info>
  <preface version="5.1">
    <info>
      <title><?xxe-sn 1uf77u7y1a8 lcmt4oo6lkbq?>VA Subject Matter Expert (SME) Panel</title>
    </info>
    <para>
      <?xxe-sn 1uf77u7y1a8 lcmt4oo6lkbr?>
      <table frame="all">
        <title>VA Subject Matter Expert (SME) Panel</title>
        <tgroup align="left" cols="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
          <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1*"
            ><?xxe-sn 1uf77u7y1a8 lcmt4oo6lkbv?></colspec>
          <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="2.29*"
            ><?xxe-sn 1uf77u7y1a8 lcmt4oo6lkbw?></colspec>
          <colspec colname="c3" colnum="3" colwidth="1.71*"
            ><?xxe-sn 1uf77u7y1a8 lcmt4oo6lkbx?></colspec>
          <thead>
            <?xxe-sn 1uf77u7y1a8 lcmt4oo6lkby?>
            <row>
              <?xxe-sn 1uf77u7y1a8 lcmt4oo6lkbz?>
              <entry>Name</entry>
              <entry>Title</entry>
              <entry>Project Role</entry>
            </row>
          </thead>
          <tbody>
            <?xxe-sn 1uf77u7y1a8 lcmt4oo6lkc3?>
            <row>
              <?xxe-sn 1uf77u7y1a8 lcmt4oo6lkc4?>
              <entry>Chris Skidmore</entry>
              <entry>
                <para>Veterans Health Administration (VHA) MST Support Team, Boston Healthcare
                  System, 150 S Huntington Ave, 4C-16, Boston, MA 02130</para>
              </entry>
              <entry>SME, Primary</entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </table>
    </para>
  </preface><preface version="5.0"><info xmlns:d="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
    <title xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">Introduction</title>
  </info>
  
<para xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  The VA is committed to improving the ability of clinicians to provide
  care for patients while increasing quality, safety, and efficiency.
  Recognizing the importance of standardizing clinical knowledge in
  support of this goal, VA is implementing the Health Level 7 (HL7)
  Knowledge Artifact Specification for a wide range of VA clinical use
  cases. Knowledge Artifacts, referred to as (KNARTs), enable the
  structuring and encoding of clinical knowledge so the knowledge can be
  integrated with electronic health records to enable clinical decision
  support.
</para>
<para xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  The purpose of this Clinical Content White Paper (CCWP) is to capture
  the clinical context and intent of KNART use cases in sufficient
  detail to provide the KNART authoring team with the clinical source
  material to construct the corresponding knowledge artifacts using the
  HL7 Knowledge Artifact Specification. This paper has been developed
  using material from a variety of sources: VA artifacts, clinical
  practice guidelines, evidence in the body of medical literature, and
  clinical expertise. After reviewing these sources, the material has
  been synthesized and harmonized under the guidance of VA subject
  matter experts to reflect clinical intent for this use case.
</para>
<para xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  Unless otherwise noted, items within this white paper (e.g.,
  documentation template fields, orderable items, etc.) are chosen to
  reflect the clinical intent at the time of creation. To provide an
  exhaustive list of all possible items and their variations is beyond
  the scope of this work.
</para>
</preface><preface version="5.1"><info xmlns:d="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
    <title xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">Conventions Used</title>
  </info>
  
<para xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  Conventions used within the knowledge artifact descriptions include:
</para>
<para xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  &lt;obtain&gt;: Indicates a prompt to obtain the information listed
</para>
<itemizedlist xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <listitem>
    <para>
      If possible, the requested information should be obtained from the underlying system(s). Otherwise, prompting the user for information may be required
    </para>
  </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>The technical and clinical notes associated with a section should be consulted for
          specific constraints on the information (e.g., time-frame, patient interview, etc.)</para>
      </listitem>
  <listitem>
    <para>
      Default Values: Unless otherwise noted, &lt;obtain&gt; indicates to obtain the most recent observation. It is recognized that this default time-frame value may be altered by future implementations
    </para>
  </listitem>
</itemizedlist>
<para xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  [...]: Square brackets enclose explanatory text that indicates some action on the part of the clinical user, or general guidance to the clinical or technical teams. Examples include, but are not limited to:
</para>
<blockquote xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <para>
    [Begin ...], [End ...]: Indicates the start and end of specific areas to clearly delineate them for technical purposes.
  </para>
  <para>
    [Activate ...]: Initiates another knowledge artifact or knowledge artifact section.
  </para>
  <para>
    [Section Prompt: ...]: If this section is applicable, then the following prompt should be displayed to the user.
  </para>
  <para>
    [Section Selection Behavior: ...]: Indicates technical constraints or considerations for the selection of items within the section.
  </para>
  <para>
    [Attach: ...]: Indicates that the specified item should be attached to the documentation template if available.
  </para>
  <para>
    [Link: ...]: Indicates that rather than attaching an item, a link should be included in the documentation template.
  </para>
  <para>
    [Clinical Comment: ...]: Indicates clinical rationale or guidance.
  </para>
  <para>
    [Technical Note: ...]: Indicates technical considerations or notes.
  </para>
  <para>
    [If ...]: Indicates the beginning of a conditional section.
  </para>
  <para>
    [Else, ...]: Indicates the beginning of the alternative branch of a conditional section.
  </para>
  <para>
    [End if ...]: Indicates the end of a conditional section.
  </para>
</blockquote>
<para xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  ਲ: Indicates items that should be selected based upon the section selection behavior.
</para>
</preface><chapter version="5.1"><info xmlns:d="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
    <title xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">Mental Health: Military Sexual Trauma (MST)</title>
  </info>
  
<section xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xml:id="clinical-context">
  <title>Clinical Context </title>
  <para>
    [Begin Clinical Context.]
  </para>
  <para>
    [Clinical Comment: Intended to support documentation of screening-related findings and decisions from screening for military sexual trauma (MST).
  </para>
  <para> The following preexisting VA materials are regarded as the preferred sources: Documentation
        Related to Military Sexual Trauma (<link
          xlink:href="https://www.mirecc.va.gov/cih-visn2/Documents/Provider_Education_Handouts/MST-Documentation_Handout.pdf)%20and%20screenshots%20from%20the%20Portland%20VA%20Medical%20Center%20(VAMC)%20(MST%20screening.docx"
          >https://www.mirecc.va.gov/cih-visn2/Documents/Provider_Education_Handouts/MST-Documentation_Handout.pdf</link>)
        and screenshots from the Portland VA Medical Center (VAMC) (MST screening.docx).] <table>
          <title>Clinical Context Domain</title>
          <tgroup cols="2">
            <colspec align="left" colwidth="97.71pt"/>
            <colspec align="left" colwidth="473.14pt"/>
            <tbody>
              <row>
                <entry>
                  <emphasis>Target User</emphasis>
                </entry>
                <entry> Any clinician (primarily used by primary care providers,
                    <emphasis>PCP</emphasis>s) </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry>
                  <emphasis>Patient</emphasis>
                </entry>
                <entry> All patients </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry>
                  <emphasis>Priority</emphasis>
                </entry>
                <entry> Routine </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry>
                  <emphasis>Specialty</emphasis>
                </entry>
                <entry> All specialties </entry>
              </row>
              <row>
                <entry>
                  <emphasis>Location</emphasis>
                </entry>
                <entry> Outpatient </entry>
              </row>
            </tbody>
          </tgroup>
        </table> [End Clinical Context.] </para>
</section>
<section xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xml:id="knowledge-artifacts">
  <title>Knowledge Artifacts</title>
  <para>
    [Begin Knowledge Artifacts.]
  </para>
  <para>
    This section describes the CDS knowledge artifact that is specific to MST. Health care professionals are required to screen all Veterans for MST and to document the results of this screening. The scope of MST is broad and includes events that may have taken place on-base or off-base, on-duty or off-duty, and perpetrated by military personnel or civilians.
  </para>
  <para>
    The knowledge artifact defines this clinical use case. The artifact is the Documentation Template and is described in detail in the following sections.
  </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>
        A Documentation Template: Mental Health: MST KNART
      </para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Supports documentation of MST related findings and decisions
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Includes logic for appropriate display of documentation sections
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>
    [End Knowledge Artifacts.]
  </para>
</section>
</chapter><chapter version="5.1"><info xmlns:d="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"><title xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">Documentation Template - Mental Health: Military Sexual Trauma (MST)</title></info>
    
    <para xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        [Begin Documentation Template – Mental Health: Military Sexual
        Trauma (MST).]
    </para>
    <para xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
        [Clinical Comment: This documentation template is appropriate for
        all patients seen in any clinical setting in the VHA; however,
        screening for MST must be done by a trained and licensed clinical
        provider as described below.]
    </para>
    <section xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xml:id="knowledge-narrative">
        <title>Knowledge Narrative</title>
        <para>
            [Begin Knowledge Narrative.]
        </para>
        <para>
            [See Clinical Context in Chapter 1.]
        </para>
        <para>
            Military sexual trauma (MST) involves exposure to one or more
            unwanted sexual experiences during military service and may be
            associated with a broad range of potential mental health and
            physical conditions, including depressive and anxiety disorders,
            posttraumatic stress disorder, substance use disorders,
            interpersonal difficulties and problems trusting others (even
            health care providers), self-blame and self-doubt, sexual
            functioning difficulties and sexual health concerns, issues
            related to sexuality and identity, difficulties navigating
            interpersonal boundaries, and increased risk of future
            victimization (“A Primer…”, VA 2011). Many specific physical
            health diagnoses have also been found to be associated with MST.
            The scope of MST is purposefully broad and includes events that
            may have been labeled as “hazing,” that took place on-base or
            off-base and while on-duty or off-duty, and that were perpetrated
            by military personnel or civilians. Health care professionals are
            required to screen all Veterans for MST and to document the
            results of this screening. All care for the mental and physical
            sequelae of MST, including pharmacologic therapy, must be provided
            free of charge. In support of that requirement, VA health care
            professionals are required to document when a visit included
            treatment for an MST-related condition. VA is also congressionally
            mandated to report on screening rates and treatment rates
            annually. Successful screening requires that clinicians be aware
            of the stigma, complexity, and sensitivity related to this
            screening. All VA clinicians are required to have completed a
            mandatory training designed to increase their knowledge, skills,
            and ability to successfully conduct the screening. Increased
            systematization and standardization of screening processes and
            tools has the potential to improve rates of identification and
            treatment of Veterans who have been victims of MST (“Military
            Sexual Trauma…”, VA 2015).
        </para>
        <para>
            [End Knowledge Narrative.]
        </para>
    </section>
    <section xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xml:id="mst-screening">
        <title>MST Screening</title>
        <para>
            [Begin MST Screening]
        </para>
        <para>
            [Section Prompt: MST Screening]
        </para>
        <para>
            [Technical Note: Provide link to Guidance for asking MST questions
            (see Appendix B).]
        </para>
        <para>
            [Technical Note: Provide link to Knowledge Resources for MST
            screening (see Appendix B).]
        </para>
        <para>
            [Section Prompt: Would it be okay if I asked about some things
            that may have happened to you while you were in the military? We
            ask all veterans these questions because VA offers free care
            related to these experiences. You can choose not to answer these
            questions if you prefer, or you may simply say 'yes' or 'no.']
        </para>
        <para>
            [Section Selection Behavior: Select one. Required.]
        </para>
        <blockquote>
            <para>
                ਲ No
            </para>
            <para>
                ਲ Yes
            </para>
            <para>
                ਲ Declines to answer
            </para>
        </blockquote>
        <para>
            [Technical Note: Selecting “No” or “Declines to answer” in the
            question above should auto-populate “Declines to answer” in the
            two following questions.]
        </para>
        <para>
            [Section Prompt: When you were in the military, did you ever
            receive unwanted, threatening, or repeated sexual attention (for
            example, touching, cornering, pressure for sexual favors, or
            inappropriate verbal remarks, etc.)?
        </para>
        <para>
            [Section Selection Behavior: Select one. Required.]
        </para>
        <blockquote>
            <para>
                ਲ No, denies prior MST
            </para>
            <para>
                ਲ Yes, reports MST in the past
            </para>
            <para>
                ਲ Declines to answer
            </para>
        </blockquote>
        <para>
            [Section Prompt: When you were in the military, did you have
            sexual contact against your will or when you were unable to say no
            (for example, after being forced or threatened or to avoid other
            consequences)?]
        </para>
        <para>
            [Section Selection Behavior: Select one. Required.]
        </para>
        <blockquote>
            <para>
                ਲ No, denies prior MST
            </para>
            <para>
                ਲ Yes, reports MST in the past
            </para>
            <para>
                ਲ Declines to answer
            </para>
        </blockquote>
        <para>
            [Technical Notes: If “Yes” is selected on either of the two
            preceding questions, display the following link to VA policy
            stating care for MST is free for the Veteran:
            https://www.gpo.gov/fdsys/pkg/USCODE-2011-title38/pdf/USCODE-2011-title38-partII-chap17-subchapII-sec1720D.pdf]
        </para>
        <para>
            [End MST Screening]
        </para>
    </section>
    <section xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xml:id="referrals-for-mst">
        <title>Referrals for MST</title>
        <para>
            [Begin Referrals]
        </para>
        <para>
            [Section Prompt: Referrals for MST]
        </para>
        <para>
            [Section Prompt: Even if the Veteran responds “no” to each
            question above or refuses screening, veterans should still be
            offered a referral to an MST specialist.]
        </para>
        <para>
            [Section Prompt: Would you like to speak to a clinical provider
            about MST treatment?]
        </para>
        <para>
            [Section Selection Behavior: Select all that apply. At least one
            selection is Required.]
        </para>
        <blockquote>
            <para>
                ਲ No, declines referral for MST treatment
            </para>
            <para>
                ਲ No, Veteran is currently in MST treatment
            </para>
            <para>
                ਲ Yes, requests referral for MST treatment
            </para>
            <para>
                ਲ Yes, requests follow up visit for physical symptoms related to
                MST
            </para>
            <para>
                ਲ Declines to answer
            </para>
        </blockquote>
        <para>
            [End Referrals]
        </para>
    </section>
    <section xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xml:id="patient-education">
        <title>Patient Education</title>
        <para>
            [Begin Patient Education]
        </para>
        <para> [Section Prompt: Patient Education] </para>
        <para>
            [Technical Note: This section should be made available if the
            answer to either question in the MST Screening section was
            "Yes."]
        </para>
        <blockquote>
            <para>
                ਲ Print MST Fact Sheet
            </para>
        </blockquote>
        <para>
            [Technical Note: clicking the checkbox above prints the document
            located at
            https://www.mentalhealth.va.gov/docs/mst_general_factsheet.pdf.]
        </para>
        <para>
            [End Patient Education]
        </para>
    </section>
    <section xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xml:id="provider-education">
        <title>Provider Education</title>
        <para>
            [Begin Provider Education]
        </para>
        <para>
            [Section Prompt: Provider Education]
        </para>
        <para>
            [Technical Note: The following references should be provided to
            users when they are selected.]
        </para>
        <para>
            Dichter ME, Wagner C, Goldberg EB, Iverson KM. Intimate partner
            violence detection and care in the Veterans Health Administration:
            patient and provider perspectives. Womens Health Issues.
            2015;25(5):555-560.
        </para>
        <para>
            Jeffreys MD, Leibowitz RQ, Finley E, Arar N. Trauma disclosure to
            health care professionals by veterans: clinical implications. Mil
            Med. 2010;175(10):719-724.
        </para>
        <para>
            Kimerling R, Street AE, Gima K, Smith MW. Evaluation of universal
            screening for military-related sexual trauma. Psychiatr Serv.
            2008;59(6):635-640.
        </para>
        <para>
            Meredith LS, Azhar G, Okunogbe A, et al. Primary care providers
            with more experience and stronger self-efficacy beliefs regarding
            women veterans screen more frequently for interpersonal violence.
            Womens Health Issues. 2017;27(5):586-591.
        </para>
        <para>
            Minsky-Kelly D, Hamberger LK, Pape DA, Wolff M. We've had
            training, now what? Qualitative analysis of barriers to domestic
            violence screening and referral in a health care setting. J
            Interpers Violence. 2005;20(10):1288-1309.
        </para>
        <para>
            Roberts ST, Watlington CG, Nett SD, Batten SV. Sexual trauma
            disclosure in clinical settings: addressing diversity. J Trauma
            Dissociation. 2010;11(2):244-259.
        </para>
        <para>
            [End Provider Education]
        </para>
        <para>
            [End Documentation Template]
        </para>
    </section>
</chapter>
  <bibliography>
    <title>Bibliography/Evidence</title>
    
    <biblioentry>
      <citetitle pubwork="article">National Veterans Health Administration Military Sexual Trauma
        Support Team. Military sexual trauma (MST) screening for professionals Materials provided by
      Chris Skidmore).</citetitle><citetitle pubwork="journal">based on original slides by Margret Bell and Kerry Makin-Byrd, in
        Skidmore Brief MST Slides.pptx, </citetitle>
      <pubdate>November 13, 2017</pubdate>
    </biblioentry>
    <biblioentry>
      <citetitle pubwork="article"> U.S. Department of Veterans Affairs. A Primer on Military Sexual
        Trauma for Mental Health Clinicians</citetitle>
      <pubdate>Published March 2011. Accessed October 26, 2017</pubdate>
      <pagenums>https://www.mirecc.va.gov/cih-visn2/Documents/Provider_Education_Handouts/MST-A_Primer_on_MST_for_Mental_Health_Clinicians.pdf</pagenums>
    </biblioentry>
    <biblioentry>
      <citetitle pubwork="article">U.S. Department of Veterans Affairs. Documentation: Related to
        Military Sexual Trauma. </citetitle>
      <pubdate>Accessed October 26, 2017</pubdate>
      <pagenums>https://www.mirecc.va.gov/cih-visn2/Documents/Provider_Education_Handouts/MST-Documentation_Handout.pdf</pagenums>
    </biblioentry>
    <biblioentry>
      <citetitle pubwork="article">U.S. Department of Veterans Affairs. Military Sexual Trauma
        Clinical Reminder Referral Question and Re-Deployment Activation Patch</citetitle>
      <citetitle pubwork="journal">PXRM*2.0*43: Installation and Setup Guide</citetitle>
      <pubdate>Published June 2015. Accessed October 26, 2017</pubdate>
      <pagenums>https://www.va.gov/vdl/documents/Clinical/CPRS-Clinical_Reminders/pxrm_2_0_43_ig.doc.</pagenums>
    </biblioentry>
    <biblioentry>
      <citetitle pubwork="article">U.S. Department of Veterans Affairs. Reminder Resolution: MST
        Screening. mst screening.docx</citetitle>
      <citetitle pubwork="journal">Veterans Administration, materials provided in Mental
        Health-20170921T220116Z-001.zip</citetitle>
      <pubdate>September 21, 2017</pubdate>
    </biblioentry>
    <biblioentry>
      <citetitle pubwork="article">Veterans’ Benefits Act, 38 USC §1720D </citetitle>
      <pubdate>2017</pubdate>
    </biblioentry>
  </bibliography><appendix version="5.1"><info xmlns:d="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
        <title xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">Existing Sample VA Artifacts</title>
    </info>
    
    <para xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">The following images are referenced from the Portland VAMC.<figure><info>
        <title>Reminder Resolution: Military Sexual Trauma (MST) Screening (image 1 of 2)</title>
    </info>
        <mediaobject>
          <alt>Screenshot of Reminder Resolution: Military Sexual Trauma (MST) Screening</alt>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata fileref="images/figure1.png"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        <figure><info>
            <title>Reminder Resolution: Military Sexual Trauma (MST) Screening (image 2 of 2)</title>
        </info>
            <mediaobject>
          <alt>Screenshot of Reminder Resolution: Military Sexual Trauma (MST) Screening</alt>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata fileref="images/figure2.png"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </figure></para>
</appendix><appendix version="5.0"><info xmlns:d="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
    <title xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">Knowledge Resources for MST screening</title>
  </info>
  
  <para xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
    Who should be screened? It is VA policy that all Veterans seen for health care be screened for <emphasis>MST</emphasis>, and it is congressionally mandated that VA report on screening rates annually.
  </para>
  <para xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
    When should screening take place? Screening should ideally occur during the Veteran’s first clinical visit. If not completed on the first visit, screening should occur as soon as possible thereafter in any subsequent visit.
  </para>
  <para xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
    If a Veteran is screened, and then has a subsequent period of military service, the screen should be re-administered upon returning to <emphasis>VA</emphasis> care (see below).
  </para>
  <para xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
    Where should the screening take place? Screening should be conducted only in private clinical settings It is never appropriate to conduct the screening in a public or group clinical setting.
  </para>
  <para xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
    Who should perform the screen? Screening should be conducted by staff with the ability and training to screen sensitively for <emphasis>MST</emphasis>, respond appropriately to disclosure, and connect Veterans with additional care or referrals as needed. Providers and/or clinical associates may screen for <emphasis>MST</emphasis>, as determined by local needs and state scope-of-licensure regulations. When screening is done by a clinical associate or registered nurse (<emphasis>RN</emphasis>) case manager, who must be familiar with the clinical considerations of screening described below, the licensed, credentialed provider associated with the visit should review the Veteran’s response and initiate a follow–up discussion during the same visit, as needed. It is never appropriate to have administrative associates screen for <emphasis>MST</emphasis>.
  </para>
  <para xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
    What follow-up is required? It is <emphasis>VA</emphasis> policy that any Veteran who reports <emphasis>MST</emphasis> be offered a referral into <emphasis>VA</emphasis> mental health care. It is <emphasis>VHA</emphasis> policy and congressionally mandated that care for <emphasis>MST</emphasis>-related mental or physical conditions be provided free of cost to the Veteran.
  </para>
  <section xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xml:id="screening-clinical-considerations">
    <title>Screening Clinical Considerations</title>
    <para>
      This section summarizes key clinical considerations when screening for <emphasis>MST</emphasis>. <emphasis>VHA</emphasis>’s mandatory <emphasis>MST</emphasis>-related training for mental health clinicians and primary care providers reviews some of the specialized knowledge and training in sensitive screening practices. Most users should have already completed one of these, but both are available in the Talent Management System (<emphasis>TMS</emphasis>) as helpful references.
    </para>
    <section xml:id="consideration-1-sensitivity">
      <title>Consideration 1: Sensitivity</title>
      <para>
        Sexual trauma is a highly sensitive, highly complex, and frequently stigmatized issue. Clinicians should maintain awareness of these factors when they proceed with screening. For example, it is important to be sensitive to barriers to disclosure, such as shame or self-blame, difficulties in trusting others, and societal stigma associated with sexual trauma (especially for male survivors). In fact, many Veterans may have received unsupportive or even blaming responses in the past if they previously disclosed <emphasis>MST</emphasis>, so it is critically important that clinicians offer patient, supportive, and empathic responses.
      </para>
      <para>
        Veterans with a history of <emphasis>MST</emphasis> may also be particularly attuned to otherwise small comments or variations in tone and body language. When screening, use clear, behaviorally based language (e.g., unwanted touching or verbal remarks) and avoid emotionally laden terms (such as “rape” or “sexual assault”), since Veterans vary in the terms they use to describe their experiences and may be hesitant to identify with more stigma-laden terms. It is also important to be aware of your behavior and body language, to make sure you communicate that you are open to hearing what Veterans have to say and that you are ready to help. For example, turn off the volume on phones and other electronic devices, and face Veterans with an attentive posture and warm facial expression.
      </para>
      <para>
        Clinicians should ask the screening questions below without reading from the embedded script word for word. This might involve practicing in advance to feel more comfortable and confident with the wording. The script is a guide, and should be followed closely, but clinicians can also integrate their own preferred language and words that suit the unique clinical encounter with each Veteran to help enhance the humanness of the conversation. How clinicians say something may be even more important than what is said. For example, clinicians should make eye contact with Veterans and speak in a quiet, calm, unrushed tone that shows comfort with asking the questions and that the answers are important to them. They should also be turned toward the Veteran, rather than looking away and reading from a computer screen, and body posture should be open and comfortable, rather than sitting forward into the Veteran’s personal space or having arms crossed as if tense or closed off to the Veteran’s responses. Even the smallest comments or variations in tone can carry great weight for survivors. For example, even asking how the <emphasis>MST</emphasis> happened or what a Veteran was wearing at the time could convey blame to the Veteran for what happened, when in fact <emphasis>MST</emphasis> is never the survivor’s fault. As another example, saying something like, “I can’t help with that,” could be perceived as a sign clinician do not want to help or hear about their concerns, or even that the entire <emphasis>VA</emphasis> does not want to help. Alternatively, saying “I’m sorry you had to go through that while you were serving your country,” in a sincere manner conveys that clinicians believe Veterans and truly care.
      </para>
      <para>
        When someone responds “yes” that he or she experienced <emphasis>MST</emphasis>, it is important to provide the following:
      </para>
      <orderedlist numeration="arabic">
        <listitem>
          <para>
            A brief, authentic, empathic response, which has the power to be tremendously healing (“I’m sorry that happened to you while you were serving your country.”)
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Education, normalization, and hope (“VA refers to this type of experience as ‘military sexual trauma’ or ‘<emphasis>MST</emphasis>,’ and <emphasis>VA</emphasis> offers free <emphasis>MST</emphasis>-related care for both physical and mental health concerns. Many Veterans have had experiences like yours and, for some, it can continue to affect them even many years later. People can recover, however.”).
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
            Information and connection with care if needed (“Would you like a referral for any physical or mental health care needs related to your experiences of <emphasis>MST</emphasis>?”).]
          </para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
      <para>
        You will see a range of reactions when a Veteran discloses an experience of <emphasis>MST</emphasis>. Some Veterans may be very emotionally flat and matter of fact; others may become very upset, crying or expressing anger. Some may answer “yes,” and then decline to provide any additional information; others might share more details about their experiences. For Veterans who choose to share details about their experiences, it is important to balance following the Veteran’s lead with using your clinical judgment about whether the Veteran may be opening up too much, too quickly. In some cases, Veterans may share more details than they would like to, almost as if they cannot help themselves, and then later regret having said so much. Sometimes they even drop out of treatment after a disclosure that made them feel too vulnerable. If you suspect a Veteran may be disclosing more details than will be helpful to them, intervene politely and supportively: “I’m so glad you feel like you can share this with me; that is really important. This may be the first time you have talked with anyone about this, though, and I just want to make sure you’re going to feel okay, later, once you leave our appointment. Talking about these sorts of experiences for the first time can often bring some relief, but it can also bring up a lot of emotions. Would it be okay to pause here for now, and transition into figuring out next steps?” As a reminder, the Veteran does not need to provide any details of the <emphasis>MST</emphasis> or any evidence that it occurred; the Veteran simply can respond “yes” to either of the screening questions, and then be provided additional information about referrals and resources by the clinician in a sensitive manner.
      </para>
      <para>
        Many providers also feel discomfort when asking about unwanted sexual experiences due to lack of training or practice, or even mistaken beliefs that this should be kept private or that survivors do not want to be asked. Instead, evidence suggests that survivors do want to be asked and will disclose in a safe environment when they feel ready. Clinicians need specialized knowledge and skills to create that safe environment, and it also requires appropriately inquiring about a referral to mental health and making one if a Veteran desires it. Clinicians also need to be prepared to answer questions about the effects of <emphasis>MST</emphasis> and <emphasis>VA</emphasis>’s free services for <emphasis>MST</emphasis>-related conditions. Training is required to do this well.
      </para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="consideration-2-privacy-and-trust">
      <title>Consideration 2: Privacy and Trust</title>
      <para>
        Given the highly sensitive nature of <emphasis>MST</emphasis> experiences, privacy is often a central concern for patients. Special care should be taken to conduct the screening, as well as any follow-up conversations, in areas that are clearly private. You are likely already sensitive to privacy as a part of your standard practice, but it is an important issue to highlight clearly when talking about <emphasis>MST</emphasis>. Survivors may be vigilant for signs that suggest you are not a safe person to talk to and may be especially attentive to potential privacy breaches. It is useful to avoid things that a survivor may perceive as potential privacy breaches, such as a desk cluttered with paper that looks like patient information or chatting about what might be mistaken as patient information in a hallway. These small signals may be very meaningful to Veterans who are considering whether to disclose experiences of <emphasis>MST</emphasis>.
      </para>
      <para>
        It is important to keep in mind that many sexual trauma survivors do not report their experiences to the authorities and that some do not tell anyone at all. Establishing rapport with the Veteran, helping reduce fear of marginalization or discrimination, and creating the general sense of a safe and trusted environment are crucial to successful screening.
      </para>
      <para>
        Disclosures may result in a wide range of reactions. Some may be emotionally flat, while others may become very upset. Some may decline to provide any additional details, while others may share extensively about their experiences. It is important to use clinical judgment in determining the appropriate response to those reactions.
      </para>
      <para>
        Privacy and Trust considerations are especially important when deciding whether the provider or a clinical associate should administer the screen.
      </para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="consideration-3-integration-into-care">
      <title>Consideration 3: Integration into Care</title>
      <para>
        Screening is a powerful opportunity to assist Veterans who have experienced <emphasis>MST</emphasis>, and it may be the first conversation a Veteran has had about experiences of <emphasis>MST</emphasis>. Receiving a supportive, empathic response can be very healing for Veterans, and this can help clinicians to assist Veterans in accessing <emphasis>MST</emphasis>-related care, if needed. Also, many Veterans will not spontaneously disclose a trauma history, so asking about <emphasis>MST</emphasis> can be the first step in getting them the help they need. The specific text of the screening instrument is intended to serve as a guide, not as definitive language. Clinicians should be able to adapt the screening language to create a more human and sensitive screening experience for each Veteran.
      </para>
      <para>
        The timing of the screening can likewise vary. Some providers choose to ask about <emphasis>MST</emphasis> in the context of discussions about the patient’s social history or military experiences. Other providers incorporate the screening within the context of broader assessments for general traumatic experiences. Another option is to ask about sexually traumatic experiences in general, and then follow up with more specific questions about whether the experiences occurred in the civilian or military setting. It is important to keep in mind that <emphasis>MST</emphasis> survivors may remain silent about their experiences. Most sexual trauma survivors do not report their experiences to authorities, and some do not tell anyone at all; some may remain silent for many years. This hesitancy to disclose can be because a Veteran does not think he/she will be believed, does not think it will make a difference to speak up, or struggles with shame or other strong feelings. A Veteran may also be concerned about stigma related to having experienced trauma or having associated mental health difficulties. Also, for marginalized groups, fear of discrimination or stereotyping can add another layer of difficulty to disclosure and help-seeking. These issues underscore the importance of creating a safe environment to facilitate disclosure, as well as providing supportive responses when disclosure does occur.
      </para>
      <para>
        Having a discussion with the Veteran about the relevance of experiences of <emphasis>MST</emphasis> for your work together conveys that this part of the Veteran’s history is important and relevant to you, and that it is safe for the Veteran to speak up about any trauma-related distress that might be experienced during your appointments or otherwise. In addition, understanding that a Veteran has a history of <emphasis>MST</emphasis> may provide critical context for the Veteran’s presenting problems. Knowledge of <emphasis>MST</emphasis> experiences can also help health care professionals in adapting care to better account for potential sensitivities or reactions to medical encounters. A history of <emphasis>MST</emphasis> may also generate issues related to trust and other complex reactions that can be better managed with knowledge of those events.
      </para>
      <para>
        The clinical reminder comes with a downloadable informational fact sheet that should be given to all Veterans who would like a copy, regardless of their decision to participate in additional care. Reaffirm that the Veteran’s experiences are relevant and that the Veteran should feel safe in discussing any trauma-related distress as needed. The current edition of the fact sheet can be retrieved from the <emphasis>VA</emphasis> Mental Health <emphasis>MST</emphasis> Internet site here: https://www.mentalhealth.va.gov/docs/mst_general_factsheet.pdf. Clinicians should also be prepared to answer potential questions about the effects of <emphasis>MST</emphasis> and about <emphasis>VA</emphasis>’s free services for <emphasis>MST</emphasis>-related conditions.
      </para>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="consideration-4-referral-to-additional-care">
      <title>Consideration 4: Referral to Additional Care</title>
      <para>
        If a Veteran reports a history of <emphasis>MST</emphasis>, it is <emphasis>VA</emphasis> policy to offer further information and connection with additional care in the form of a referral question embedded in the <emphasis>MST</emphasis> screen (also referred to as the Clinical Reminder below). For Veterans who express an interest in further care, the regular referral process at that local VA facility should be followed. Some facilities will automatically inform the facility <emphasis>MST</emphasis> Coordinator upon completion of the clinical reminder.
      </para>
      <para>
        Many Veterans who experienced <emphasis>MST</emphasis> may genuinely be recovering well and do not need care. Alternatively, some Veterans may simply not yet be ready to engage in care. For this reason, when a Veteran declines a referral, it is useful to first validate and respect that, and then also keep the door open for the future: “If you ever change your mind and want to speak to someone, just let me or one of your other providers know.”
      </para>
      <para>
        In addition, a Veteran’s response of “no” to the <emphasis>MST</emphasis> questions may be a genuine “no.” In case it is not, and the Veteran is just not ready to disclose an <emphasis>MST</emphasis> experience, leave the door open for future disclosure: “I’m glad to hear that. I asked because VA has free, specialized services to help Veterans who’ve had these sorts of experiences, so I wanted to make sure to talk to you about those resources if they are relevant now or ever become relevant in the future.”
      </para>
    </section>
  </section>
  <section xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xml:id="guidance-with-asking-mst-screening-questions">
    <title>Guidance with asking MST Screening Questions</title>
    <para> Would it be okay if I asked about some things that may have happened to you while you
        were in the military? We ask all veterans these questions because VA offers free care
        related to these experiences. You can choose not to answer these questions if you prefer, or
        you may simply say 'yes' or 'no.'</para>

      <blockquote>
        <para>
          ਲ No
        </para>

        <para>
          ਲ Yes
        </para>

        <para>
          ਲ Declines to answer
        </para>
      </blockquote>
    <para>
      For Veterans who do not decline, the clinician should proceed with asking the following questions, with a comfortable tone and good eye contact, and using the script below as a guide. It should not be read verbatim, but clinicians can have the <emphasis>MST</emphasis> Clinical Reminder open on a computer screen or printed out in a packet of standard screening paperwork in their lap if needed as a reference. The language below may be phrased in a slightly different way if necessary to capture language that the clinician is comfortable with in that encounter with that specific Veteran, as long as it fully captures both categories of unwanted sexual experiences.
    </para>
    <para>
      When you were in the military, did you ever receive unwanted, threatening, or repeated sexual attention (for example, touching, cornering, pressure for sexual favors, or inappropriate verbal remarks, etc.)?
    </para>

      <blockquote>
        <para>
          ਲ No, denies prior <emphasis>MST</emphasis>
        </para>

        <para>
          ਲ Yes, reports <emphasis>MST</emphasis> in the past
        </para>

        <para>
          ਲ Declines to answer
        </para>
      </blockquote>
    <para>
      When you were in the military, did you have sexual contact against your will or when you were unable to say no (for example, after being forced or threatened or to avoid other consequences)?
    </para>

      <blockquote>
        <para>
          ਲ No, denies prior <emphasis>MST</emphasis>
        </para>

        <para>
          ਲ Yes, reports <emphasis>MST</emphasis> in the past
        </para>

        <para>
          ਲ Declines to answer
        </para>
      </blockquote>

    <para>
      If a Veteran answers “yes” to either question, the clinician must be mindful to respond in a sensitive, compassionate, and validating manner. For example: “I am very sorry you had to experience that while serving your country. Thank you so much for sharing that information with me. It will help me to better understand what you are going through. <emphasis>VA</emphasis> refers to this as ‘military sexual trauma’ or ‘<emphasis>MST</emphasis>,’ and we offer free care to men and women for physical and mental health concerns related to <emphasis>MST</emphasis>. Would you like to speak with a provider about this care?” However, the clinician does not need to prompt or ask for more details about the experience, and the Veteran does not need to have told anyone or have any evidence that the <emphasis>MST</emphasis> occurred. Service connection is also not required to receive <emphasis>MST</emphasis>-related services. If instead a Veteran answers “no,” the clinician should respond with a comment such as, “Thank you. I ask all Veterans these questions, because VA offers free care related to these experiences, and we want to make sure all Veterans are aware of this.”
    </para>
  </section>
  <section xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xml:id="patient-education2">
    <title>Patient Education</title>
    <para>
      OPTIONAL PHRASES:
    </para>
    <orderedlist numeration="arabic">
      <listitem>
        <para>
          Thank you for sharing that with me. <emphasis>VA</emphasis> refers to this type of experience as 'military sexual trauma' or <emphasis>'MST</emphasis>,' and <emphasis>VA</emphasis> offers free <emphasis>MST</emphasis>-related care for both physical and mental health concerns.
        </para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para> Thank you so much for sharing that information with me. It will help me to better
            understand what you are going through. VA wants Veterans to know about common
            difficulties related to <emphasis>MST</emphasis> and <emphasis>VA’s</emphasis> free
              <emphasis>MST</emphasis>-related services, so it created a factsheet that we can give
            out to Veterans. It describes what <emphasis>MST</emphasis> is, how MST may affect you,
            and how to get help if you would like it. Would you mind if I printed it out and gave it
            to you to take with you? I am also happy to answer any questions you have. Every
            facility also has an <emphasis>MST</emphasis> Coordinator who is a point person for
            Veterans on <emphasis>MST</emphasis>-related issues. This facility’s
              <emphasis>MST</emphasis> Coordinator is _________.</para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <para>
      Clinicians should be ready to discuss the handout contents if needed.
    </para>
  </section>
  <section xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xml:id="referrals-for-mst2">
    <title>Referrals for MST</title>
    <para>
      Even if the Veteran responds “no” to each question above or refuses screening, veterans should still be offered a referral to an MST specialist.
    </para>
    <para>
      Ask the patient: Would you like to speak to a clinical provider about MST treatment?
    </para>
   
      <blockquote>
        <para> ਲ No, declines referral for <emphasis>MST </emphasis> treatment</para>

        <para>
          ਲ No, Veteran is currently in MST treatment
        </para>

        <para>
          ਲ Yes, requests referral for <emphasis>MST</emphasis> treatment
        </para>

        <para>
          ਲ Yes, requests follow up visit for physical symptoms related to MST
        </para>

        <para>
          ਲ Declines to answer
        </para>
      </blockquote>

    <para>
      Veterans who request a referral should be connected to mental health services in a timely manner consistent with local policy and procedures. Facilities will vary on how referral requests are handled. Clinicians should explain the referral process to the Veterans and what they can expect next.
    </para>
    <para>
      In addition, Veterans may say ‘yes’ to the referral question but intend to request a referral only for physical health conditions. It is clinicians’ responsibility to assess the nature of Veterans’ requests for a referral and to make appropriate referrals for <emphasis>MST</emphasis>-related physical health conditions via other means if that is the main or an additional need. Also, when a Veteran screens positive for MST in primary care and requests a referral for mental health services, primary care team members are encouraged to consider providing a warm hand-off to a primary care mental health provider whenever possible.
    </para>
    <para>
      1) A Veteran’s subjective experience is sufficient for a positive screen; 2) Can occur on or off base, while a Veteran was on or off duty; 3) Perpetrator identity does not matter; 4) Notes that all health care services (inpatient, outpatient, and pharmaceutical care) for physical and mental health conditions related to <emphasis>MST</emphasis> are provided free of charge. In addition, Veterans with additional military service after their original <emphasis>MST</emphasis> Clinical Reminder has been completed (for both “yes” and “no” responses) need to be rescreened after they separate from the service again, as they have had additional opportunity for exposure to <emphasis>MST</emphasis>.
    </para>
  </section>

</appendix>
  <appendix><title>Acronyms</title><para>
      <informaltable>
        <tgroup cols="2">
          <colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="101.14pt"/>
          <colspec colnum="2" colname="col2" colwidth="293.57pt"/>
          <tbody>
            <row>
              <entry>ADSMs</entry>
              <entry>Active Duty Service Members</entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry>CCWP</entry>
              <entry>Clinical Content White Paper</entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry>CDS</entry>
              <entry>Clinical Decision Support</entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry>DoD</entry>
              <entry>Department of Defense</entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry>HL7</entry>
              <entry>Health Level 7</entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry>KBS</entry>
              <entry>Knowledge Based Systems</entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry>KNART</entry>
              <entry>Knowledge Artifact</entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry>MST</entry>
              <entry>Military Sexual Trauma</entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry>OIIG</entry>
              <entry>Office of Informatics and Information Governance</entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry>PCP</entry>
              <entry>Primary Care Provider</entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry>RN</entry>
              <entry>Registered Nurse</entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry>SME</entry>
              <entry>Subject Matter Expert</entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry>TMS</entry>
              <entry>Talent Management System</entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry>TO</entry>
              <entry>Task Order</entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry>VA</entry>
              <entry>Department of Veterans Affairs</entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry>VAMC</entry>
              <entry>VA Medical Center</entry>
            </row>
            <row>
              <entry>VHA</entry>
              <entry>Veterans Health Administration</entry>
            </row>
          </tbody>
        </tgroup>
      </informaltable>
    </para></appendix></book>
