<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.1/rng/docbook.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.1/rng/docbook.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<book xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.1">

    <info>
        <title>Gastroenterology (GI): Colonoscopy Harmonize and Integrate Member KNARTs White
            Paper</title>
        <releaseinfo>Contract: VA118-16-D-1008, Task Order (TO): VA-118-16-F-1008-0007,
            CLIN0006AB</releaseinfo>
        <pubdate>6/11/2018</pubdate>
        <volumenum>Version: 1.0</volumenum>
        <author>
            <orgname>Department of Veterans Affairs (VA)</orgname>
        </author>
        <mediaobject>
            <alt>Department of Veteran's Affairs Logo</alt>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata contentwidth="2in" align="center" fileref="images/va-logo.png"
                    format="png"/>
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
        <authorgroup>
            <author>
                <orgname>Knowledge Based Systems (KBS)</orgname>
            </author>
            <author>
                <orgname>Office of Informatics and Information Governance (OIIG)</orgname>
            </author>
            <author>
                <orgname>Clinical Decision Support (CDS)</orgname>
            </author>
        </authorgroup>
        <revhistory>
            <revision>
                <revnumber>1.0</revnumber>
                <date>6/11/2018</date>
                <authorinitials>Jerry Goodnough</authorinitials>
                <revremark>Final</revremark>
            </revision>
        </revhistory>
        <copyright>
            <year>2018</year>
            <holder>B3 Group, Inc.</holder>
        </copyright>
        <legalnotice>
            <title>B3 Group, Inc.</title>
            <para>NOTICE OF GOVERNMENT COPYRIGHT LICENSE AND UNLIMITED RIGHTS LICENSE</para>
            <para>Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License"); you may not use
                this file except in compliance with the License.</para>
            <para>You may obtain a copy of the License at <link
                    xlink:href="http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0"
                    >http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0</link>
            </para>
            <para>Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software distributed
                under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS, WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR
                CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied. See the License for the specific
                language governing permissions and limitations under the License.</para>
            <para>Portions of this content are derivative works from content produced by Cognitive
                Medical Systems, Inc. licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0.</para>
            <para>Additional portions of this content are derivative works from content contributed
                by Motive Medical Intelligence Inc., under Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike
                4.0.</para>
            <para>Contributions from 2013-2018 were performed either by US Government employees, or
                under US Veterans Health Administration contracts.</para>
            <para>US Veterans Health Administration contributions by government employees are work
                of the U.S. Government and are not subject to copyright protection in the United
                States. Portions contributed by government employees are USGovWork (17USC §105). Not
                subject to copyright.</para>
            <para>See: <link xlink:href="https://www.usa.gov/government-works"
                    >https://www.usa.gov/government-works</link>
            </para>
            <para>Contribution by contractors to the US Veterans Health Administration during this
                period are contractually contributed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 and US
                Government sponsorship is acknowledged under Contract VA118-16-D-1008, Task Order
                VA11817F10080007.</para>
        </legalnotice>
        <copyright>
            <year>2018</year>
            <holder>Cognitive Medical Systems, Inc.</holder>
        </copyright>
        <legalnotice>
            <title>Cognitive Medical Systems, Inc.</title>
            <para>Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License"); you may not use
                this file except in compliance with the License.</para>
            <para>You may obtain a copy of the License at <link
                    xlink:href="http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0"
                    >http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0</link>
            </para>
            <para>Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software distributed
                under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS, WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR
                CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied. See the License for the specific
                language governing permissions and limitations under the License.</para>
            <para>This and related content produced by Cognitive Medical Systems, Inc. licensed
                under the Apache License, Version 2.0 is available at: <link
                    xlink:href="https://bitbucket.org/cogmedsys/hl7-kas-examples"
                    >https://bitbucket.org/cogmedsys/hl7-kas-examples</link>
            </para>
            <para>Additional portions of this content are derivative works from content contributed
                by Motive Medical Intelligence Inc., under Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike
                4.0. <link xlink:href="https://bitbucket.org/cogmedsys/kas-source-material"
                    >https://bitbucket.org/cogmedsys/kas-source-material</link>
            </para>
            <para>Contributions from 2013-2018 were performed either by US Government employees, or
                under US Veterans Health Administration contracts.</para>
            <para>US Veterans Health Administration contributions by government employees are work
                of the U.S. Government and are not subject to copyright protection in the United
                States. Portions contributed by government employees are USGovWork (17USC §105). Not
                subject to copyright. See: <link xlink:href="https://www.usa.gov/government-works"
                    >https://www.usa.gov/government-works</link>
            </para>
            <para>Contribution by contractors to the US Veterans Health Administration during this
                period are contractually contributed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 and US
                Government sponsorship is acknowledged under Contract VA118-16-D-1008-0007.</para>
        </legalnotice>
    </info>



    <chapter>
        <title>General Process</title>
        <para>In integrating and harmonizing the individual components of a composite knowledge
            artifact (KNART), the general process has been to rely on the inherent encapsulation
            properties envisioned in the new composite structure. Each individual knowledge artifact
            is presumed to be able to run in a stand-alone and independent manner. The composite
            artifact acts as a central orchestration agent, activating individual knowledge
            artifacts using an event-driven model. Intercommunication between artifacts is handled
            solely through global shared state external to the composite and through the process of
            event payloads. Individual KNARTs only communicate with the composite container.</para>
        <para>During the creation of the individual KNARTs used in the formation of the composite,
            their design and implementation explicitly envisioned their further integration into a
            composite structure. As such, minimal harmonization or communication is generally
            required. All composite KNARTs use references to the individual component knowledge
            artifacts rather than direct inclusion. The general design principles used should ensure
            that the overall composite does not alter the essential information contained in the
            components.</para>
        <para>The emerging composite KNART standard envisions that the parent composite will not
            restate the metadata included in its component parts unless there is a clinical or
            technical need to override or supplement the information contained in the components.
            This includes elements such as supporting evidence, intended use, etc. Analysis of the
            components of this KNART did not find the need to make any overrides or supplements to
            the essential metadata.</para>
        <para>In developing the Version 2.0 KNART standard, the work group has updated the essential
            file structure to support composites. The design approach of the workgroup was to define
            the composite mechanism to support composition that includes both literal inclusion and
            references to other KNARTs. The emerging standard explicitly envisions that composites
            may be of a heterogeneous nature and supports artifacts authoring in other forms. The
            creation of the Version 2 schema explicitly maintains backward compatibility. The
            Version 1 knowledge document schema was structured such that the introduction of
            composite feature could not be made without breaking backward compatibility. As a
            result, internal organization of the schema was refactored to isolate the concept of a
            knowledge document and create two potential root references, which could be used
            depending on whether the KNART was a singleton or a composite. The Version 2 schema
            supports the composite structures, references, and direct inclusion of multiple
            knowledge documents. All the elements of the original document type are still
            supported.</para>
        <section xml:id="section_myy_snv_ndb">
            <title>Overview of Integration Scenario</title>
            <para>This composite uses an integration scenario whereby an Event-Condition-Action
                (ECA) rule is first used to screen whether a consult is required and which order
                sets are needed. If the screening is indicated (see the section “Clinical Statement
                Indicating Screening Should Occur”), then the documentation template is projected
                and requested order sets are then activated. All orchestration is accomplished
                through embedded ECA rules in the composite.</para>
        </section>
        <section xml:id="section_pgj_bt1_c2b">
            <title>Clinical Statement Indicating Screening Should Occur</title>
            <para>A clinical statement with the following characteristics indicates screening should
                occur. If no such statement after the ECA rules is run, then no other events should
                    occur.<informaltable frame="all">
                    <tgroup cols="2">
                        <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1*"/>
                        <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1*"/>
                        <thead>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Characteristic</entry>
                                <entry>Details</entry>
                            </row>
                        </thead>
                        <tbody>
                            <row>
                                <entry>statementType</entry>
                                <entry>398166005 |Performed (qualifier value)|</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>topic</entry>
                                <entry>444783004 |Screening colonoscopy (procedure)</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>result.status</entry>
                                <entry>410525008 |Needed (qualifier value)|</entry>
                            </row>
                        </tbody>
                    </tgroup>
                </informaltable></para>
        </section>
        <section xml:id="section_u4f_mt1_c2b">
            <title>Order Set Mapping to the ECA Rules</title>
            <para>Analysis of the ECA rules controlling this composite indicate that only three
                order sets are used. Ideally, the clinical statements requesting these would have
                unique nodes, but at the time of this composition all "should" statements were coded
                as “TSR-NoCode.” In order to allow the composite to act correctly, these statements
                have been updated to include an unstructured[0] property with unique identification
                that equates to the intended order set. The table that follows lists the value of
                the property and which order is intended.<informaltable frame="all">
                    <tgroup cols="3">
                        <colspec colname="c1" colnum="1" colwidth="1*"/>
                        <colspec colname="c2" colnum="2" colwidth="1*"/>
                        <colspec colname="c3" colnum="3" colwidth="1*"/>
                        <thead>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Value</entry>
                                <entry>#</entry>
                                <entry>UUID</entry>
                            </row>
                        </thead>
                        <tbody>
                            <row>
                                <entry>UnknownTerm_OS_ARS</entry>
                                <entry>B26</entry>
                                <entry>f26871e4-c788-5242-a53c-cb061d431158</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>UnknownTerm_OS_FH</entry>
                                <entry>B21</entry>
                                <entry>c2d53d08-af01-594b-a670-d8fc2bf71da6</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>UnknownTerm_OS_FIT</entry>
                                <entry>B27</entry>
                                <entry>c0ec00f7-ceb0-5f72-ba14-10a7e0042b89</entry>
                            </row>
                        </tbody>
                    </tgroup>
                </informaltable></para>
        </section>
        <section xml:id="section_nyy_snv_ndb">
            <title>General Limitations</title>
            <para>The composite KNART is a machine-readable artifact comprised of independently
                validated components. The goal of the composition is not to add additional content
                but rather to orchestrate the individual components. The composite is not expected
                to be machine executable. The schema and functional environment in which the
                composite is created is based on an emerging standard and is not guaranteed to be
                compatible with the final balloted standard.</para>
            <section xml:id="section_wcy_b4v_ndb">
                <title>Format Limitation</title>
                <para>The proposed Health Level Seven International (HL7) KNART format for
                    composites is based on the original Knowledge Artifact Specification (KAS)
                    schema. The composite extension is specifically developed to allow the
                    composition of these singleton KAS artifacts into an organizing structure to
                    provide greater meaning. The composite KNART format is an emerging standard at
                    HL7 that allows heterogeneous artifacts to be grouped into one common organizing
                    document. In creating the composite knowledge artifacts, the individual
                    components of the composite have been limited to the existing KAS-derived
                    artifact types. As such, the abstraction of more advanced orchestration behavior
                    has been limited to the capabilities of that model.</para>
            </section>
        </section>
    </chapter>
    <chapter>
        <title>Process of Harmonization</title>
        <section xml:id="section_pyy_snv_ndb">
            <title>General Process</title>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Detailed review of composite components</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Map components to conceptual white paper</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Consultation on workflow with authoring team</para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </section>
        <section xml:id="section_qyy_snv_ndb">
            <title>Organization</title>
            <para>At an organizational level, this composite is comprised of five major entities.
                The first of these entities is an ECA rule used to determine screening template and
                order set applicability, named CDSK_KRprt_ECA_B1ColoCanScr.xml. The consult
                documentation template is named CDSK_KRprt_CRDT_B42Colos.xml. Finally, there are
                three order sets, named CDSK_KRprt_OS_B26ColosRskScr.xml,
                CDSK_KRprt_OS_B21ColosFH.xml, and CDSK_KRprt_OS_B27ColosFIT.xml .</para>
            <para>For the purposes of orchestration, the composite initially triggers an event
                causing the ECA rule to be activated. Upon completion of the ECA rule, if screening
                is in order, the documentation template is triggered and the requested order set
                knowledge artifacts are activated.</para>
        </section>
        <section xml:id="section_ryy_snv_ndb">
            <title>Data</title>
            <section xml:id="section_tbn_4f3_qdb">
                <title>Orchestration Data Elements</title>
                <para>All orchestration for this composite is handled by the examination and
                    assertion of named events. The following table lists the events are used to
                    drive the key behavior in this composite.</para>
                <informaltable>
                    <tgroup cols="3">
                        <colspec colnum="1" colname="col1"/>
                        <colspec colnum="2" colname="col2"/>
                        <colspec colnum="3" colname="col3"/>
                        <thead>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Event Name</entry>
                                <entry>Event Type</entry>
                                <entry>Relevant Payload</entry>
                            </row>
                        </thead>
                        <tbody>
                            <row>
                                <entry>FireECACheck</entry>
                                <entry>Named event</entry>
                                <entry>None</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>ECACheckComplete</entry>
                                <entry>Named event</entry>
                                <entry>ECACheckComplete.ClinicalStatement</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>FireDocTemplate</entry>
                                <entry>Named event</entry>
                                <entry>None</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>FireAverageRiskOS</entry>
                                <entry>Named event</entry>
                                <entry>None</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>FireFamilyHistoryOS</entry>
                                <entry>Named event</entry>
                                <entry>None</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>FireFITTestOrderSet</entry>
                                <entry>Named event</entry>
                                <entry>None</entry>
                            </row>
                        </tbody>
                    </tgroup>
                </informaltable>
            </section>
            <section xml:id="section_tyy_snv_ndb">
                <title>Redundant Data Elements Within KNARTs</title>
                <para> Not applicable.</para>
            </section>
            <section xml:id="section_uyy_snv_ndb">
                <title>Near-Duplicates Within KNARTs</title>
                <para> Not applicable.</para>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title> Redundant References, Supporting Evidence, and Expressions Within
                    KNARTs</title>
                <para> Not applicable.</para>
            </section>
            <section xml:id="section_vyy_snv_ndb">
                <title>Data Elements That Are to be Hidden From the User</title>
                <para> Not applicable.</para>
            </section>
        </section>
        <section xml:id="section_wyy_snv_ndb">
            <title>Questions Being Asked of the Documenter</title>
            <section xml:id="section_xyy_snv_ndb">
                <title>General</title>
                <para>All questions being asked of the documenter are delegated to the specific
                    component parts. Readers are asked to refer to the details of the composite
                    parts. No additional questions are asked by the composite itself.</para>
            </section>
            <section xml:id="section_yyy_snv_ndb">
                <title>Specific to the Composite</title>
                <para> Not applicable.</para>
            </section>
        </section>
        <section xml:id="section_zyy_snv_ndb">
            <title>Organization of Order Sets</title>
            <para>There are there threee order sets, of which only two might be activated on a
                single pass. The ECA rules determine which order sets to activate. Either the
                Average Risk or the Famility Histrory order set is actaivated, and after that the
                Order Fecal Immunochemical Test (FIT) Test order set if needed.</para>
        </section>
    </chapter>
    <chapter>
        <title>Integration</title>
        <section xml:id="section_bzy_snv_ndb">
            <title>Process</title>
            <para>The general process integration is based upon the detailed reading of the
                composite clinical white paper and the individual constituent components. Functional
                analysis of the expected data flow and event flow between the created entities was
                used to construct this composite. </para>
        </section>
        <section xml:id="section_czy_snv_ndb">
            <title>Concerns</title>
            <para>In reviewing the structure and questions asked of the documentation template, it
                is not clear that all the elements required to fully create a referral are being
                asked. It is suggested that either a standardized referral documentation template be
                created and used for composites or that a detailed review of the documentation
                template for the additional required information is conducted prior to proceeding to
                an implementation phase. </para>
        </section>
        <section xml:id="section_dzy_snv_ndb">
            <title>Assets</title>
            <para>The following table lists the assets that make up this composite.</para>
            <informaltable>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colnum="1" colname="col1"/>
                    <colspec colnum="2" colname="col2"/>
                    <colspec colnum="3" colname="col3"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry>Asset Filename</entry>
                            <entry>Description</entry>
                            <entry>ANF Version</entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>CDSK_KRprt_CRCK_B59RA.xml</entry>
                            <entry>The main composite controller</entry>
                            <entry>1.0</entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>CDSK_KRprt_ECA_B1ColoCanScr.xml</entry>
                            <entry>The screening &amp; order set determination ECA</entry>
                            <entry>1.0</entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>CDSK_KRprt_CRDT_B42Colos.xml</entry>
                            <entry>The documentation template</entry>
                            <entry>1.0</entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>CDSK_KRprt_OS_B26ColosRskScr.xml</entry>
                            <entry>The average risk order set</entry>
                            <entry>1.0</entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>CDSK_KRprt_OS_B21ColosFH.xml</entry>
                            <entry>The family history order set</entry>
                            <entry>1.0</entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>CDSK_KRprt_OS_B27ColosFIT.xml</entry>
                            <entry>The FIT test order set</entry>
                            <entry>1.0</entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </informaltable>
            <para> </para>
        </section>
    </chapter>
</book>
