<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.1/rng/docbook.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.1/rng/docbook.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<book xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.1">

    <info>
        <title>Cardiology: Pre-Op Risk Assessment Harmonization and Integration White Paper</title>
        <releaseinfo>Contract: VA118-16-D-1008, Task Order (TO): VA-118-16-F-1008-0007,
            CLIN0006AB</releaseinfo>
        <pubdate>05/30/2018</pubdate>
        <volumenum> Version: 1.0</volumenum>
        <author>
            <orgname>Department of Veterans Affairs (VA)</orgname>
        </author>
        <mediaobject>
            <alt>Department of Veteran's Affairs Logo</alt>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata contentwidth="2in" align="center" fileref="images/va-logo.png"
                    format="png"/>
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
        <authorgroup>
            <author>
                <orgname>Knowledge Based Systems (KBS)</orgname>
            </author>
            <author>
                <orgname>Office of Informatics and Information Governance (OIIG)</orgname>
            </author>
            <author>
                <orgname>Clinical Decision Support (CDS)</orgname>
            </author>
        </authorgroup>
        <pubdate>May 2018</pubdate>
        <volumenum>Version 1.0</volumenum>
        <revhistory>
            <revision>
                <revnumber>1.0</revnumber>
                <date>5/30/2018</date>
                <authorinitials>Jerry Goodnough</authorinitials>
                <revremark>Final</revremark>
            </revision>
        </revhistory>
    </info>



    <chapter>
        <title>General Process</title>
        <para>In integrating and harmonizing the individual components of a composite knowledge
            artifact (KNART) the general process has been to rely on the inherent encapsulation
            properties envisioned in the new composite structure. Each individual knowledge artifact
            is presumed to be able to run in a standalone and independent manner. The composite
            artifact acts as a central orchestration agent, activating individual knowledge
            artifacts using an event driven model. Intercommunication between artifacts is handled
            solely through global shared state external to the composite and through the process of
            event payloads. Individual knowledge artifacts only communicate with the composite
            container.</para>
        <para>During the creation of the individual knowledge artifacts used in the formation of the
            composite their design and implementation explicitly envisioned their further
            integration into a composite structure. As such, minimal harmonization or communication
            is generally required. All composite KNARTs use references to the individual component
            knowledge artifacts rather than direct inclusion. The general design principles used
            should ensure that the overall composite does not alter the essential information
            contained in the components.</para>
        <para>The emerging composite KNART standard envisions that the parent composite will not
            restate the metadata included in its component parts unless there is a clinical or
            technical need to override or supplement the information contained in the components.
            This includes such elements such as supporting evidence, intended use, etc. Analysis of
            the components of this KNART did not find the need to make any overrides or supplements
            to the essential metadata.</para>
        <para>In developing the Version 2.0 KNART standard the work group has updated the essential
            file structure to support composites. The design approach of the workgroup was to define
            the composite mechanism to support composition the includes both literal inclusion and
            references to other knowledge artifact. The emerging standard explicitly envisions that
            composites may be of a heterogeneous nature and supports artifacts authoring in other
            forms. The creation of the version 2 schema explicitly maintains backward compatibility.
            The version 1.0 knowledge document schema was structured such that the introduction of
            composite feature could not be made without breaking backward compatibility. As a
            result, internal organization of the schema was refactored to isolate out the concept of
            a knowledge document and create two potential root references which could be used
            depending on if the KNART was a singleton or a composite. The version 2 schema superset
            of the prior schema - Which is to say that singletons follow the older schema
            (reorganized structurally) and the new composite document type supports the composite
            structures, references, and direct inclusion of multiple knowledge documents. All the
            elements of the original document type are still supported without breaking
            anything.</para>
        <section xml:id="section_myy_snv_ndb">
            <title>Overview of Integration Scenario</title>
            <para>This composite uses a simple integration scenario whereby the documentation
                template is first projected and based upon applicability information captured in
                that template, the order set is selectively activated. All orchestration is
                accomplished through embedded Event Condition Action (ECA) Rules in the
                composite.</para>
        </section>
        <section xml:id="section_nyy_snv_ndb">
            <title>General Limitations</title>
            <para>The composite KNART is a machine-readable artifact comprised of independently
                validated components. The goal of the composition is not to add additional content
                but rather to orchestrate the individual components. The composite is not expected
                to be machine executable. The schema and functional environment in which the
                composite is created is based on an emerging standard and is not guaranteed to be
                compatible with the final balloted standard.</para>
            <section xml:id="section_wcy_b4v_ndb">
                <title>Format Limitation</title>
                <para>The proposed Health Level 7 (HL7) KNART format for composites is based on the
                    original Knowledge Artifact Specification (KAS) schema. The composite extension
                    is specifically developed to allow the composition of these singleton KAS
                    artifacts into an organizing structure to provide greater meaning. The composite
                    KNART format is an emerging standard at HL7 that allows heterogeneous artifacts
                    to be grouped into one common organizing document. In creating the composite
                    knowledge artifacts, the individual components of the composite have been
                    limited to the existing KAS derived artifact types. As such the abstraction of
                    more advanced orchestration behavior has been limited to the capabilities of
                    that model.</para>
            </section>
        </section>
    </chapter>
    <chapter>
        <title>Process of Harmonization</title>
        <section xml:id="section_pyy_snv_ndb">
            <title>General Process</title>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Detailed review of composite components</para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>Map components to conceptual white paper</para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </section>
        <section xml:id="section_qyy_snv_ndb">
            <title>Organization</title>
            <para>At an organizational level this composite is comprised of two major entities. The
                first of these entities is the documentation template named B37CRDT – Cardiology:
                Pre-Op Risk Assessment Documentation Template. The second of these entities is the
                order set named B13OS – Cardiology: Pre-Op Order Set. For the purposes of
                orchestration the composite initially triggers an event causing the documentation
                template to be activated. Upon the completion of the documentation template the
                completion event is analyzed to validate that the exclusion criteria was not met.
                Specifically, acknowledgment that the documentation template is not applicable to
                emergency surgery patients or patients with an acute coronary syndrome, will result
                the order set knowledge artifact activated.</para>
        </section>
        <section xml:id="section_ryy_snv_ndb">
            <title>Data</title>
            <section xml:id="section_syy_snv_ndb">
                <title>Special Bindings</title>
                <para>The Preoperative documentation template did not specify a specific response
                    binding for the reason for Documentation Template Applicability. For the
                    purposes of making the composite it is assumed that a default binding scenario
                    is used. The standard binding is to use the explicitly defined binding if
                    present, if such a binding is not present then a default scheme is assumed. In
                    the default scheme, if an DocumentationConcept.identifier id is present then
                    this will become the binding symbol. Should there be no
                    DocumentationConcept.identifier then the binding is based on the prompt used.
                    The Name used for the binding is the prompt stripped of all punctuation and
                    white space. For example, in the case the Documentation template used the prompt
                    “Acknowledge:” which results in a symbolic name on “Acknowledge”. If in creating
                    a default symbol name there is a conflict in generated names, then that name
                    will contain a zero-based array of the responses in the order they appear in the
                    template. It should be noted that scheme is not expected to make it in to the
                    standard, but rather the response binding is expected to become a required
                    element of a Collect Information Action. In the case of this composite the first
                    occurrence of “Acknowledge” is used. </para>
            </section>
            <section xml:id="section_qgj_mf3_qdb">
                <title>Orchestration Data Elements</title>
                <para>All orchestration for this composite is handled by the examination and
                    assertion of named events. The following table lists the events are used to
                    drive the key behavior in this composite.</para>
                <informaltable>
                    <tgroup cols="3">
                        <colspec colnum="1" colname="col1"/>
                        <colspec colnum="2" colname="col2"/>
                        <colspec colnum="3" colname="col3"/>
                        <thead>
                            <row>
                                <entry>Event Name</entry>
                                <entry>Event Type</entry>
                                <entry>Relevant Payload</entry>
                            </row>
                        </thead>
                        <tbody>
                            <row>
                                <entry>FireDocTemplate</entry>
                                <entry>Named event</entry>
                                <entry>none</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>DocumentationCompleteEvent</entry>
                                <entry>Named event</entry>
                                <entry>Responses.Acknowledge[0]</entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>FireOrderSet</entry>
                                <entry>Named event</entry>
                                <entry>none</entry>
                            </row>
                        </tbody>
                    </tgroup>
                </informaltable>
            </section>
            <section xml:id="section_tyy_snv_ndb">
                <title>Redundant Data Elements Within KNARTs</title>
                <para>None. </para>
            </section>
            <section xml:id="section_uyy_snv_ndb">
                <title>Near-Duplicates Within KNARTs</title>
                <para>None.</para>
            </section>
            <section>
                <title> Redundant References, Supporting Evidence, and Expressions Within
                    KNARTs</title>
                <para>None due to execution and encapsulation model of the contained
                    artifact.</para>
            </section>
            <section xml:id="section_vyy_snv_ndb">
                <title>Data Elements That Are to be Hidden From the User</title>
                <para> Not applicable.</para>
            </section>
        </section>
        <section xml:id="section_wyy_snv_ndb">
            <title>Questions Being Asked of the Documenter</title>
            <section xml:id="section_xyy_snv_ndb">
                <title>General</title>
                <para> All questions being asked of the documenter are delegated to the specific
                    component parts. Readers are asked to refer to the details of the composite
                    parts. No additional questions are asked by the composite itself.</para>
                <para> </para>
            </section>
            <section xml:id="section_yyy_snv_ndb">
                <title>Specific to the Composite</title>
                <para> None.</para>
            </section>
        </section>
        <section xml:id="section_zyy_snv_ndb">
            <title>Organization of Order Sets</title>
            <para>Only one order set is present in this composite. </para>
        </section>
    </chapter>
    <chapter>
        <title>Integration</title>
        <section xml:id="section_bzy_snv_ndb">
            <title>Process</title>
            <para>The general process integration is based upon the detailed reading of the
                composite clinical White paper and the individual constituent components. Functional
                analysis of the expected data flow and event flow between the created entities was
                used to construct this composite. </para>
        </section>
        <section xml:id="section_czy_snv_ndb">
            <title>Concerns</title>
            <para>In reviewing the structure and questions asked of the documentation template it is
                not clear that all the elements required to fully create a referral are being asked.
                It is suggested that either a standardized referral documentation template be
                created and used for composites or that a detailed review of the documentation
                template for the additional required information be conducted prior to proceeding to
                an implementation phase. Analysis of the documentation template shows that it does
                not selectively engage its questions based on the applicability question.</para>
        </section>
        <section xml:id="section_dzy_snv_ndb">
            <title>Assets</title>
            <para>The following table lists the assets that make up this composite.</para>
            <informaltable>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colnum="1" colname="col1"/>
                    <colspec colnum="2" colname="col2"/>
                    <colspec colnum="3" colname="col3"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry>Asset filename</entry>
                            <entry>Description</entry>
                            <entry>ANF version</entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>CDSK_KRprt_CRCK_B58CardPreOp.xml</entry>
                            <entry>The main composite controller</entry>
                            <entry>0.9,1.0</entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>CDSK_KRprt_CRDT_B35CardPreOp.xml</entry>
                            <entry>The documentation template</entry>
                            <entry>1.0</entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>CDSK_KRprt_OS_B37CardPreOp.xml</entry>
                            <entry>The order set</entry>
                            <entry>1.0</entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </informaltable>
            <para> </para>
        </section>
    </chapter>
</book>
